Let’s talk about closing the presentation
I don’t want to end the presentation too abruptly
just because I’m running out of time
So plan a “graceful exit” for your presentation
Signal your audience that the presentation
is coming to an end. You can say
“That brings me to the end of my presentation”
or “If no one else has any questions, let’s stop here”
If they are interested in learning more about the subject
you can provide additional information.
Something like “You can read more about this
via the links on the screen.”
Or, “Here is a list of some readings on this topic.”
The audience will certainly appreciate the extra help
You might start feeling tired
and exhausted toward the end
Remember to keep up your energy
and enthusiasm until the last minute
Good reminder
We want to start well and end well.
You need to finish on a high note
That means you should complete
your presentation at a successful point
Yes. A powerful ending should leave
a lasting impression on your audience.
How about ending with a call to action?
Sometimes we want the audience
to react and respond to our message
and put words into action.
Right. Some of my favorite
call-to-action lines are: “Join the fight,”
“Take action” and “Make a difference.”
Those are some strong and powerful action words
That’s something an audience can take home with them.
Also, use positive action verbs
such as “I urge you…”, “Get involved”
or “Partner with us.”
You hope to receive feedback from your audience
This kind of call to action will motivate them
to respond to what they hear.
That’s a good point
You should also thank your audience again
for their time and for paying attention
to your presentation
Say something like
I appreciate you giving me the time
to share my ideas with you
or Thank you for your kind attention
or even a simple, Thank you for listening
That’s very good
I am sure the audience would like to hear that
It should make a perfect ending to your presentation
Thank you both for your suggestions and tips
I am going back to work on my presentation now
I know it’ll be a good one
Yes. Now you are making a positive
and encouraging ending to our conversation, too!